expath.de 2017-12-20

# Privacy Policy - Expath

Hi there and welcome to our privacy policy!

  1. **Commitment**

Expath is committed to respecting your privacy whilst providing the highest possible quality service and we recognize the need to know that your personal data is being lawfully processed and to be compliant with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Personal data is any information that relates to a living individual who can be identified by that data and covers the information you may provide to us. Expath will never sell your private information or share your email or postal address with third parties, as well as teachers, fellow students and workshop participants or other clients, unless you request us to do so.

  2. **Purpose**

Expath provides you with the information set out in this Privacy Statement so that if you share your personal data with us you are aware of what we do with it.

  3. **Data Controller**

Expath is the data controller of your personal data. Our contact details are listed below. The DPO is Stephan Brenner.

  4. **Data Collection**

We collect necessary information from you when you, for example when you register, when you email us, make online purchases, fill out the feedback or contact forms, sign up for the newsletter or take our online placement test, or if you supply this information in person, on the phone or via social media or any other instances where you choose to share this information with us. This data may include:

Your name

Your email address

Your company name, address, telephone number

This information is collected from the online forms you complete and submit to Expath, or via email, on the phone, on social media or in person.

  5. **Use of Personal Data**

We use the information that you personally provide to:

Improve the information and support we provide

Process any requests you make

Bill properly (e.g. invoicing) and track payment

Process feedback and course/coaching/workshop administration

Schedule courses, workshops and coachings

Have all necessary information to offer personalized coachings

Provide you with information about products and services we offer

Notify agents/affiliates of referral sales, if applicable (first name and last initial only) to analyze the effectiveness of marketing efforts

In the interests of continually improving our services, we may contact you from time-to-time inform you of new products and services that are relevant to you, such as follow-up courses, feedback or our newsletter.

We are committed to giving you the choice of whether or not to receive such information.

The data is kept either until you request removal, or until it is deemed obsolete. This data can be accessed, updated or removed at your request.

  6. **Sensitive Information**

We will never collect sensitive information about you without your express consent, such as your credit card information or social security number. No payments are processed on our site, but rather externally via bank transfer, PayPal or through cash transactions.

  7. **Transfer of Personal Data**

Data transferred outside of the EEA (European Economic Area) may include your first name and last initial in case you were referred to our site and made a purchase by an agent/affiliate located outside the EEA, as well as aggregate, non-personally identifiable statistical information.

  8. **Third Parties use of your Personal Data**

Expath will not sell your personal data to others. Expath may share your name and necessary contact details with our coaches, interpreters and translators if it is necessary to ensure that external coachings and translations happen at the agreed place and time. In some situations, Expath may share only your first name and last initial with agents/affiliates in case you were referred to our site by an agent/affiliate and made a purchase.

  9. **Accuracy**

Expath strives to keep your personal data up to date and accurate. We will amend or delete inaccurate data as soon as reasonably practical after a request from you to do so. You may request details of personal information which we hold about you.

  10. **Tracking**

We also collect information automatically about your visit to our Site. The information obtained in this way, which includes demographic data and browsing patterns, is only used in aggregate form, and as such cannot be used to identify you personally. Such aggregate information helps us to audit usage of our website and improve the service provided.

  11. **Security**

Expath is committed to ensuring the security of your personal data. In order to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of your personal data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

  12. **Changes**

Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted here.

  13. **Contact Us**

If you have comments or questions about our Privacy Statement, please email them to info@expath.de .

Thanks and have a great day!

Your Expath Team
